# **Alaina Kafkes**

#### **Awards**

## Anita Borg Institute GHC Scholar

**June 2016.** Won an all-expenses paid trip to the Grace Hopper Celebration for excellence in innovation & leadership.

#### PanHellenic Scholar

**May 2016.** Received a merit scholarship that honors exceptional undergraduates of Greek-American heritage.

## Personal Projects

#### Dibz

#### January 2016 – June 2016.

Founded and developed a web app that offers online sellers the ability to generate a bitlink to share a listing in informal, online communities. Launched to 50+ beta testers in June 2016. Technologies used: Javascript, RiotJS, Firebase API, HTML/CSS.

#### Rude

#### February 2016 (HackIllinois).

Coded Android app that encourages users to spend quality time socializing without checking their phone. Technologies used: Java, Facebook API.

#### July 2016 – Present.

Developing Rude as an iPhone app. Languages used: Swift.

#### Myrror

#### January 2016 - March 2016.

Developed a web app cast onto a two-way mirror that assesses the user's body confidence using the principles of social comparison theory and waist size approximations. Pitched proof of concept to 50+ students and professors, which was selected to be pursued by faculty of the Feinberg School of Medicine. Technologies used: Javascript, JQuery, Firebase API.

### Education

Northwestern University | Computer Science, minor in Chemistry

Anticipated June 2017. Cumulative GPA: 3.69/4.00

## Work Experience

## GE Healthcare | Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 – Present. Developing the Media Manager web application, which expedites the binding of images & videos to patient data in the Centricity Clinical Archive. Spearheaded the creation of a mock server to prevent unit testing with sensitive patient information. Technologies used: AngularJS 2, NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, C#, HTML/CSS.

# Northwestern University | Teaching Assistant

**December 2015 – Present.** Assists students in introductory programming course through the creation of a network and with object-oriented programming questions. Languages used: C++.

## National Science Foundation | REU Intern

**June 2015 – August 2015.** Coded scripts that computationally optimized aluminum-biomolecule conjugates in order to find a cheap alternative to gold and silver in biodiagnostics. One of twenty young engineers selected for a prestigious National Science Foundation fellowship. Languages used: Python.

## Extracurriculars & Offices Held

## Women in Computing | Internal President

**April 2015 – Present.** Established and chairs first-ever mentorship program for undergraduate & graduate women in tech, with 40+ participants in the pilot program. Organizes and teaches at weekly, campus-wide hack nights for 100+ attendees. Founded women's hackathon (projected April 2017).

# EPIC | Project Lead & Web Developer

**April 2016 – Present.** Built website for the Northwestern Venture Challenge. Technologies used: Sass, Gulp, Javascript, HTML/CSS.

## Peer Health Exchange | Senior Health Educator

**September 2014 – Present.** Teaches the ninth grade health & sexual education curriculum at Chicago Public Schools.

# Kappa Delta Sorority | Academic Excellence Chair

**November 2015 – Present.** Hosted Kappa Delta's first-ever resume building workshop and launched chapter-wide resume database.